# **Andrew Richardson**

andyandy698@gmail.com - 615-424-6893 - www.linkedin.com/in/andrew-roland-richardson

Frontend Engineer with 4 years of total experience, with 3 years in Frontend development, 1 year in Mobile/Full Stack development, and strong skills in React, JavaScript/TypeScript, Redux, Storybook, and Cl/CD pipelines.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Tanium**Remote (Nashville, TN)
Software Engineer
Feb 2022 – Present

Co-led a team on a brand-new product/service; led technical design process and created an MVP that
was pitched to leadership and approved for production; managed and led development from initial
development to QA to production.

Postscript Remote (Nashville, TN)
Frontend Engineer 2 Jun 2021 – Feb 2022

- Worked with design as the sole engineer to lead a revamp of the entire UI/UX of the web application in three months; this included user & market research, prototyping, planning, and execution.
- Improved and stream-lined the CI/CD of organization's repositories and reduced development time by up to 10%.

**Asurion**Full Stack Software Engineer 2
Nashville, TN
Jan 2020 – Jun 2021

 Helped establish a team of roughly eight engineers to build a Wi-Fi diagnostic service. Introduced CI/CD and reusable code (using Lerna and Yarn workspaces) to cut down development time of features by up to 40% and grew the product to one of Asurion's most profitable services.

Amazon Austin, TX

Software Development Engineer Intern

May 2019 – August 2019

 Built an internal company tool to improve the speed and quality of communications between other teams and the Mobile Homepage team by automating the mobile homepage card development process.

**Healthware Consortium** *React Native Software Engineer* 

Franklin, TN May 2018 – May 2019

• Converted an Objective-C and Swift based iOS app into a cross-platform React Native application with a backend and API consisting of Enterprise Java and an SQL database.

### **EDUCATION**

**Frontend Guild** 

# **University of Alabama in Huntsville**

Huntsville, AL

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

#### INVOLVEMENT & LEADERSHIP

0.0.4.75.374.6.84.4.

@Asurion & Postscript

Co-Creator / Facilitating Member

- Bi-Weekly meeting for Frontend Engineers in the Product organization
- Facilitate organization wide growth in technical & interpersonal skills, and the use of new technologies while also solidifying and unifying organization-wide tech stack

### **SKILLS**

• React, JavaScript/TypeScript, Redux, Storybook, Cypress, Jest, Figma, CI/CD, Git